Guide to the Arthur A. Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Arthur A. Cohen papers
1941-1988
YCAL MSS 496
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
47
(46 boxes)
The Arthur A. Cohen Papers provide evidence of the writing, editing, and publishing career of Arthur Allen Cohen between 1940 and 1986. The Papers consist of correspondence, writings, personal papers, photographs, audiovisual material, legal and financial documents, and clippings relating to Cohen's writing, publishing companies Noonday Press and Meridian Books, and work editing the Documents of Twentieth Century Art series for Viking Press. Cohen's interest in theology (particularly Judaism) and art are also reflected in the Papers, particularly his writing and publishing projects.
Cohen, Arthur A. (Arthur Allen), 1928-1986
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Arthur A. Cohen and Elaine Lustig Cohen, 1985-2010.
Conditions Governing Access
Boxes 38 and 46 (audiovisual material): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Existence and Location of Copies
Correspondence with Robert Motherwell (November 1985 and January 1986 Acquisitions) is available on microfilm.
Arthur A. Cohen (1928-1986)
Arthur Allen Cohen, theologian, author, editor, and publisher, was born on June 25, 1928 in New York to Isidore Meyer and Bess Junger Cohen. Cohen graduated from the University of Chicago with a Bachelor of Arts (1946) and a Masters of Arts (1949). He returned to New York where he enrolled at the Union Theological Seminary and the Jewish Theological Seminary of America (graduating in 1953).
While Cohen was a student at the Jewish Theological Seminary he founded the Noonday Press with Cecil Hemley. Cohen sold the press in 1955 and founded Meridian Books. When the World Publishing Company bought Meridian Books in 1960, Cohen stayed on with the company, working as vice president until taking a position as director of the religious book department and then editor-in-chief at Holt, Rinehart, & Winston (1962-64). Cohen worked as managing editor of the Documents of Twentieth Century Art series for Viking Press from 1968 to 1975.
Cohen also sustained a writing career in tandem with his publishing career. He authored several novels, including The Carpenter Years (1967), In the Days of Simon Stern (1973), A Hero in His Time (1976), Acts of Theft (1980), An Admirable Woman (1983), and Artists and Enemies (1987). His non-fiction works include Martin Buber (1957), The Natural and the Supernatural Jew (1962), The Myth of the Judeo-Christian Tradition (1970), Osip Emilievich Mandelstam: An Essay in Antiphon (1974), and The Tremendum: A Theological Interpretation of the Holocaust (1981). Cohen also published a number of articles in Harper's, New York Times Book Review, Partisan Review, and other journals.
In 1956 Cohen married Elaine Firstenberg Lustig (b. 1927), a graphic designer, painter, and photographer, with whom he opened Ex Libris (1974-1986), a gallery and bookstore specializing in rare, out-of-print materials on twentieth-century art (particularly European avant-garde). Arthur and Elaine Cohen had one daughter, Tamar Judith, an artist based in New York.
Cohen died of cancer at the age of 58 in 1986.
Scope and Contents
The Arthur A. Cohen Papers provide evidence of the writing, editing, and publishing career of Arthur Allen Cohen between 1940 and 1986. The Papers consist of correspondence, writings, personal papers, photographs, audiovisual material, legal and financial documents, and clippings relating to Cohen's writing, publishing companies Noonday Press and Meridian Books, and work editing the Documents of Twentieth Century Art series for Viking Press. Cohen's interest in theology (particularly Judaism) and art are also reflected in the Papers. Cohen's Papers provide insight into theology, the art world, and publishing during the mid-twentieth century.
The progression of Cohen's creative process from idea to publication is documented in correspondence, drafts, and printed material pertaining to his books. For example, the Papers include drafts, galleys, publicity, reviews, and other material tracing Cohen's novel In the Days of Simon Stern. Correspondence with publishers, such as Random House and Ardis Publishing House, also pertain to Cohen's writing career. Cohen's interest in religion is reflected in several of his writing projects as well as correspondence with theologians such as Thomas J. J. Altizer, Jacob Neusner, and Jacob Taubes.
Cohen's literary circle included a number of authors, such as Yoram Kaniuk, Jerzy Kosinski, Jacques Maritain, David McKain, Ron Padgett, Ruthven Todd, and Elie Wiesel, some of whose works he edited and published. In addition, Cohen's correspondence with artist Robert Motherwell reflects their friendship and work editing Viking Press's Documents of Twentieth Century Art series (Motherwell served as the general editor whereas Cohen worked as the managing editor). As the Papers illustrate, Cohen also wrote the foreword to a book by and about Motherwell, printed as part of the series.
Correspondence and papers concerning Meridian Books, Noonday Press, and the Documents of Twentieth Century Art series relate to Cohen's publishing career. Also of interest is Cohen's correspondence with Morris Philipson, a student with Cohen at the University of Chicago, who went on to be the director of the University of Chicago Press.
Cohen's correspondence with friends, family (largely his parents Isidore Meyer and Bess Junger Cohen), photographs, and journals also provide insight into his personal life.
Arrangement
Organized into nine groupings: I. November 1985 and January 1986 Acquisitions, 1959-1982. II. August 1987 Acquisition, 1957-1981. III. February 1990 Acquisition, undated. IV. October 1991 Acquisition, circa 1986. V. April 1992 Acquisition, 1960s-1970s. VI. November 1992 Acquisition, 1960s. VII. January 1993 Acquisition, undated. VIII. October 2003 Acquisition, 1941-1988. IX. December 2010 Acquisition, 1940s-1980s.
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Editors -- United States; Publishers and publishing -- United States; Judaism -- Doctrines; Judaism -- 20th Century; Theologians -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Photographs; Sound recordings; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Theologians; Altizer, Thomas J. J., 1927-; Cohen, Arthur A. (Arthur Allen), 1928-1986; Kaniuk, Yoram, 1930-2013; Kosinski, Jerzy, 1933-1991; Maritain, Jacques, 1882-1973; Motherwell, Robert, 1915-1991; Neusner, Jacob, 1932-2016; Taubes, Jacob, 1923-1987; Todd, Ruthven, 1914-1978; Wiesel, Elie, 1928-2016; Meridian Books; Noonday Press; Viking Press
- November 1985 and January 1986 Acquisitions, 1959-1982; 8.75; (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Typescripts and galleys of several works by Cohen, including In the Days of Simon Stern; papers relating to the Committee on Church and State; papers concerning Meridian Books; correspondence, including letters from Robert Motherwell and Elie Wiesel; and subject files, most concerning various works by Cohen.
  General note
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 3
  - Meridian correspondence, accountant's reports (Box 1)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, printer's marked up set and design sheets (Box 1)
  - "The Messiah is Uptown", 4 (Box 1)
  - "Kaplan," draft (Box 2)
  - "Constructionism and Neo-Classicism" (Box 2)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, 4 (Box 2)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, author's set, 3 (Box 2)
  - "Fund for the Republic," printed, 4 (Box 3)
  - "Fund for the Republic," paper, 4 (Box 3)
  - "Fund for the Republic," files, 4 (Box 3)
  - Wiesel, Elie, correspondence (Box 4)
  - Kaniuk, Yoram, correspondence (Box 4)
  - Altizer, Thomas J. J. correspondence ("Beyond the Death of God") and writings, 3 (Box 4)
  - Scully, James (Box 4)
  - Bermant, Chaim (Box 4)
  - Philipson, Morris, correspondence (Box 4)
  - Maritain, Jacques, correspondence (Box 4)
  - McKain David, correspondence, 1970- (Box 4)
  - Motherwell-Cohen, contracts (Box 4)
  - Motherwell, Robert, correspondence, Documents of Twentieth Century Art, 2 (Box 4)
  - Kosinski, Jerzy, correspondence (Box 4)
  - Heer, F., correspondence (Box 4)
  - Lynch, William SJ, correspondence (Box 4)
  - Philippe Soupault, Ex Libris (Box 4)
  - Todd, Ruthven, correspondence (Box 4)
  - Todd, Ruthven-Cohen, Arthur A. (Box 4)
  - Padgett, Ron (Box 4)
  - Neusner, Jacob (Box 4)
  - Schapiro, David, 2 (Box 4)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, reviews (Box 5)
  - "The Law of Reason in Kuzari"-typescript of essay Leo Strauss (Box 5)
  - Taubes, Jacob (Box 5)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, reader reactions (Box 5)
  - A Hero In His Time, Martin Secker & Warburg correspondence (Box 5)
  - A Hero in His Time, publicity (Box 5)
  - Osip Emilievich Mandelstam: An Essay in Antiphon, publicity (Box 5)
  - The Natural and the Supernatural Jew, English Edition (Box 5)
  - The Natural and Supernatural Jew, publisher correspondence (Box 5)
  - The Natural and Supernatural Jew, German edition by Karl Alber Verl (Box 5)
  - The Natural and Supernatural Jew, English edition, Vallentine, Mitchell (Box 5)
  - "The Jewish Mind," manuscript, notes (Box 5)
  - Meridian book specifications (Box 6)
  - Random House-Arthur Allen Cohen (Box 6)
  - Ardis Publishing House (Box 6)
  - B'nai B'rith commission on adult Jewish education, "Excellence," talk at luncheon B'nai B'rith, 1966 March 13 (Box 6)
  - Aspen conference (Box 6)
  - American friends of Ichud (Box 6)
  - American Jewish congress (Box 6)
  - "Reflections on the History of Jewish Thought," and "The Past and Future of Eschatological Thinking," RELIGION AND CONTEMPORARY SOCIETY, Macmillan, 1963 (Box 6)
  - "Reflections on the History of Jewish Thought," RELIGION AND CONTEMPORARY SOCIETY, Macmillan (Box 6)
  - Danforth lectures, "Eschatology," Barnard, 1962 January (Box 6)
  - Humanistic Education and Western Civilization, ed. Cohen, Holt, Rinehart & Winston, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Christianity: a Non Christian Appraisal," essay, ed. McKaim, McGraw-Hill (Box 6)
  - "Hans Cassebeer and the Virgin's Rose," TriQuart, 33 (Box 6)
  - Martin Buber, reviews and letters (Box 6)
  - "American Catholics: A Jewish View" (Box 6)
  - If Not Now, When? (Box 6)
  - If Not Now, When?, reviews and comments (Box 6)
  - "American Catholics: a Protestant-Jewish View", 1959 (Box 6)
  - Martin Buber, "Studies in Modern European Culture and Literature" (Box 6)
  - The Natural and Supernatural Jew, review and comments (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, "Russian Diary" of Alfred (Box 7)
  - Poets and writers, CODA (Box 7)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, board of directors, 1983 (Box 7)
  - The Carpenter Years (Box 7)
  - The Carpenter Years (Box 7)
  - The Carpenter Years, US: New American Library, UK: Hart-Davis Ltd (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, correspondence with publishers (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, publicity department (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, correspondence with Random House (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, paper edition, Delta Books (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, Sales Department (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, "The Last Jew on Earth," commentary (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, Israel (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, Edward Lewis Wallant prize, 1974 (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, correspondence W. G. Borchardt (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, response (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, work in progress (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, midstream, job (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, Random House, advertising (Box 7)
  - A Hero in His Time, reading with Navrozo, YMNA, 1976 January (Box 7)
  - A Hero in His Time, movie (Box 7)
  - A Hero in His Time, misc. correspondence (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, manuscript materials (Box 7)
  - The Carpenter Years, Hart Davis Ltd, 1967 March (Box 7)
  - "The Truth is Not Enough," short story, 1966 Fall (Box 7)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, fragments (Box 7)
- August 1987 Acquisition, 1957-1981; 12.5; (10 boxes)
  Typescripts and galleys of several works including In the Days of Simon Stern, Martin Buber, and A Hero in His Time.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 48
  - Acts of Theft, original manuscript, 1977-1979; 2 (Box 8)
  - An Admirable Woman, original manuscript, 1979-1981; 2 (Box 9)
  - Artists and Enemies, 2 (Box 10)
  - "Herbert Bayer: The Complete Work" (Box 10)
  - Arguments and Doctrines: A Reader in Jewish Thinking (Box 10)
  - The Carpenter Years, 1965-1967; 4 (Box 11)
  - A People Apart: Hasidism in America, 1970 (Box 11)
  - A Hero in His Time, 1973-1975; 2 (Box 12)
  - The Natural and the Supernatural Jew, 1957-1962; 2 (Box 13)
  - The Jew: Essays from Martin Buber's Journal "Der Jude" (Box 13)
  - Osip Emilievich Mandelstam: an Essay in Antiphon, 1974 (Box 14)
  - The Myth of the Judeo-Christian Tradition, 1970 (Box 14)
  - The Tremendum, research materials and manuscripts, 1979-1981 (Box 14)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, 1966-1972 (Box 15)
  - Humanistic Education and Western Civilization: Essays for Robert Hutchins, circa 1964 (Box 15)
  - If Not Now, When?, conversations of Kaplan and Cohen, 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - The Natural and the Supernatural Jew, 3 (Box 16)
  - Martin Buber, 1957 (Box 17)
  - In the Days of Simon Stern, 1966-1972 (Box 17)
- February 1990 Acquisition, undated; 3 (Box 18)
  Holograph notes on an education in philosophy.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA File 234
- October 1991 Acquisition, circa 1986; 0.83; (2 boxes) (Box 18–19)
  Correspondence and writings by, to, or relating to Arthur Allen Cohen; includes letters from Paul Mendes-Flohr, Elizabeth Elston, and others concerning A Handbook of Jewish Theology, and correspondence relating to the Jewish Museum exhibit "In the Beginning".
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 207
- April 1992 Acquisition, 1960s-1970s; 2.5; (2 boxes) (Box 20–21)
  Arguments and Doctrines, typescript, with correspondence; The Carpenter Years, typescript; In the Days of Simon Stern, typescript; Diaries by Franz Rosenzweig, translated by Jehuda Reiz; notes and notebooks by Arthur Allen Cohen relating to history, philosophy, and Judaism and related papers.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 265
- November 1992 Acquisition, 1960s; 0.42; (1 box) (Box 22)
  The Gates of the Forest and The Madness of God by Elie Wiesel, translated by Arthur A. Cohen, typescripts; Zalmen ou la Folie Dieu, by Elie Wiesel, in French, typescript; correspondence and printed material relating to Arthur A. Cohen.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 390
- January 1993 Acquisition, undated; 0.42; (1 box) (Box 23)
  Correspondence, notes, typescripts, printed material, and book jackets of works by Arthur Allen Cohen.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 276
- October 2003 Acquisition, 1941-1987; 19.54; (18 boxes)
  Correspondence, writings, including reviews, 6 audio tapes, 4 records, 2 reel to reel tapes, printed material and personal papers.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 563
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 38 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Book review, undated (Box 24)
  - Published articles, 1951 (Box 24)
  - "The Encounter of Judaism and Christendom," Cross Currents No. 3, 1951 (Box 24)
  - Israel Life and Letters, Volume VII No. 3, 1951 (Box 24)
  - "Eclipse of God" by Buber, Judaism, 1952 (Box 24)
  - "Revelation and Law", 1952 (Box 24)
  - "Eclipse of God" by Martin Buber, 1953 (Box 24)
  - "Revelation and Law in Buber," Judaism, 1953 (Box 24)
  - Reviews in Judaism, 1954 (Box 24)
  - "Messianism and the Jew," Commonweal Vol. LXII No. 15, 1955 (Box 24)
  - "Ideology of Religious Secularism," Partisan Review, 1956 (Box 24)
  - "On Scriptural Exegesis," Cross Currents Vol. V No. 1, 1955 (Box 24)
  - Letter: Answer to Sidney Hook's "Six Fallacies of Robert M. Hutchins," The New Leader, 1956 (Box 24)
  - Halpern, Ben, 1956, undated (Box 24)
  - Articles, 1956 (Box 24)
  - "Moses, Mystery, and Jesus," Jewish Frontier, 1956 (Box 24)
  - Review of Nathaniel West's Holy Fool, Commonweal, 1956 (Box 24)
  - Church and State, Park Ave Synagogue, 1956 (Box 24)
  - "Nathaniel West and the Holy Fool," Commonweal, 1956 (Box 24)
  - "The Bridge," review article, Frontier, 1956 (Box 24)
  - "Contemporary Problems in Religions," review, Judaism, 1956 (Box 24)
  - "Religion as a Secular Ideology," Partisan Review, 1956 (Box 24)
  - Articles, 1957 (Box 24)
  - "The Plight of Judaism," Commonweal, 1957 (Box 24)
  - "American Judaism" by Nathaniel Glazer, review for Christian Century, 1957 (Box 24)
  - "Pacifism," The Jewish Frontier, 1957 (Box 24)
  - "Toynbee and Samuel," The Jewish Frontier and review of "An Historian's Approach" by Toynbee, Church Peace Union News, 1956-1957 (Box 24)
  - "For a New Center of Creativity," The New Leader, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Excerpt from Cohen's book on Buber, Martin Buber: "The Bible and Hasidism," Jewish Frontier, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, The Jewish Press, Commonweal, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Review of "The Bridge" for Judaism, 1957 (Box 24)
  - "Spiritual Semites?," Christian Century, 1957 (Box 24)
  - "Three We Have Lost," Conservative Judaism, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Martin Buber, Maurice Friedman, Conservative Judaism, 1956, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Review of "Prayer, Humility and Compassion," Conservative Judaism, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Review of "Course of Modern Jewish History" by Sachar, Saturday Review, 1958 (Box 24)
  - "The Search for Values" Address to the Hillel Foundation, Brandeis, November 24, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Reviews, 1958 (Box 24)
  - "Natural and Supernatural Jew" Israel Goldman Lecture, Harvard Hillel, 1958 (Box 24)
  - "On Natural Law," A Comment on Gustave Weigel, S J Essay on Natural Law, Worldview, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Review of "Hasidism and Modern Man," The Saturday Review, 1958 (Box 24)
  - "The Jewish Christian Contradiction," Worldview, 1958 February (Box 24)
  - Handbook of Christian Theology, articles on Judaism and Atheism, 1958 (Box 24)
  - "Religion in a Free Society," essay for The Fund for the Republic, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Santayana Letter (note for Publication in Partisan Review ), 1958 (Box 24)
  - Review, "Who's Offending Whom?," The Christian Century, 1958 April (Box 24)
  - Review, "Hasidism and Modern Man" by Maurice Freidman, Saturday Review, 1958 (Box 24)
  - "The Seminary and the Modern Rabbi", 1959 (Box 24)
  - Review of "David" by D. H. Lawrence, Christian Century, 1958 April (Box 24)
  - "Why I Choose to Be a Jew," Harper's Magazine, 1959 April (Box 24)
  - Journals, 1959 (Box 24)
  - "Why I Choose to Be a Jew," Harper's Magazine, 1959 April (Box 24)
  - "On Judaism and Catholicism," I and II, Reconstructionist Vol. XXV No. 6 and XXV No. 8, 1959 (Box 24)
  - "A Book Publisher Uses Graphic Design," Art in America, 1959 (Box 24)
  - Articles, 1959 (Box 24)
  - Journals, 1959 (Box 24)
  - The New Leader, 1960 (Box 24)
  - A Reply to the Critics "Anatomy of Faith" edited by Arthur A Cohen, Conservative Judaism, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Radio talk, "American Catholics; A Jewish View," AAC & Gustave Weigel, S.J., The Catholic Hour, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Danford Lectures, Barnard, Judaism, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Ameryka, 1959 (Box 24)
  - "My Jewish Affirmation" Symposium, 10th Anniversary Issue, Judaism Magazine, 1961 (Box 25)
  - Discussion, comments from a meeting published in Our Age, books for Jewish Students/High School, 1961 (Box 25)
  - Kaufmann, Commentary, Review of "The Faith of Heretic", 1962 January (Box 25)
  - Journals, 1962 (Box 25)
  - Reviews, undated (Box 25)
  - Preface for Triangle, 1962 (Box 25)
  - "Notes Toward a Jewish Theology of Politics," Commonweal, 1962 September 29 (Box 25)
  - "Franz Rosenweig's The Star of Redemption: An Inquiry into its Psychological Origins," Midstream, 1972 February (Box 25)
  - "In the Aftermath Silence," Christianity and Crisis, 1962 June (Box 25)
  - "Plurality, Not Pluralism," Lecture, Villanova Institute Church & State, 1962 July 12 (Box 25)
  - Letter to Editor, America, 1962 April 7 (Box 25)
  - "The Evil We Know Not Of," Lecture, Meninger Foundation, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Lecture "The Philosopher and the Jew," University of Wisconsin, Hebrew Studies and Philosophy, Published in Judaism, 1962 (Box 25)
  - Hahn Festschrift (70 Birthday), 1963 (Box 25)
  - "Paperbacks in the College," College and Research Libraries, paper given at University of Michigan Conference on Paperbacks February 2, 1962, 1963 March (Box 25)
  - Journals, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Review of "German Catholics and Hitler's Wars" by Zahn, Worldview, 1963 September (Box 25)
  - Architecture, Synagogue Symposium, 1963 November 7 (Box 25)
  - Speech, "The Absence of Heroism," Worldview, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Perspectives on the Good Society: A Jewish-Protestant Colloquium, 1963 April 23 (Box 25)
  - Booklists of the Christian Century, Cohen, 1963 January 2 (Box 25)
  - "Toward a Theology of Jewish Existence," Series in Christian Century, 1963 January 23 (Box 25)
  - Letter, "An Uncontentious Responsum to Will Herberg (the Natural and Supernatural Jew)," Judaism, 1963 (Box 25)
  - "The Negative Way," lithographs by Paul Brach, text by Arthur A. Cohen, 1965 (Box 25)
  - "The Hebrew Bible in Christian, Jewish and Muslim Art," The Jewish Museum, Organized by Cohen, catalog, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1963 (Box 25)
  - "The Jew, Secularity and Christian Culture," Ramparts Vol. II No. 2, 1963 (Box 25)
  - "The Jew, Secularity, and Christian Culture," Ramparts and Lecture, Woodstock College, Published in Ramparts, 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - "Jewish Philosophy," Sacramentum Mundi, Catholic Theological Lexicon, 1969 (Box 25)
  - Review of Hugo Rahner's "Pursuit of Christian Archetypes (Greek Myths and Christian Mystery)," Commonweal, 1965 February 14 (Box 25)
  - "In Search of the Divine," review of John Courney Murray's "The Problem of God," The Critic, 1964 (Box 25)
  - "The Temper of Jewish Anti-Christianity: A Theological Statement," Christianity: Some Non-Christian Appraisals, 1964 (Box 25)
  - Journals, 1964 (Box 25)
  - Review of Cohen's book "The Natural and Supernatural Jew" by Friedrich Heer, The Christian Century, 1964 May 13 (Box 25)
  - What's Ahead for the Churches, Sheed & Ward, 1964 (Box 25)
  - Review (The Deputy), "History in the Guise of Drama," Christianity and Crisis, Vol. XXIV No. 5, 1964 March 30 (Box 25)
  - Review, "Rediscovering Judaism," The Commonweal, 1965 January (Box 25)
  - "Martin Buber," American Judaism, 1965 October (Box 25)
  - "Nietzsche" by Karl Jaspers, New York Herald Tribune, 1965 September (Box 25)
  - The Newman Center Lectures, University of Minnesota, 1965 January (Box 25)
  - "A Jew's Lament," Ramparts, 1965 October (Box 25)
  - "Freedom How," review of Stuart Hampshire's "Freedom of the Individual," New York Times, 1965 December 5 (Box 25)
  - Journals, 1965 (Box 25)
  - Colloquy, Stendahl, Yoder and Cohen Fellowship (Implications of Peace on Earth conference), 1965 May (Box 25)
  - "What About Jewish Art?" Symposium, Jewish Museum, 1965 January 7 (Box 25)
  - "Buber and Maritain" Symposium, Manhattanville Coll. Sacred Heart, 1966 January 31 (Box 25)
  - "Between Two Traditions," Midstream, 1966 (Box 25)
  - Midstream Symposium on Negroes and Jews, Vol. XI No. 10, 1966 December (Box 25)
  - Review of "Athens and Jerusalem" by Lev Shestov, 1966 (Box 25)
  - Journals, 1966 (Box 25)
  - "Varieties of Jewish Belief," J. Reconstructionist Fndn., 1966 (Box 25)
  - "McLuhan and the Visual-Verbal Culture," American Institute of Graphic Arts Dinner Address, 1966 April 18 (Box 25)
  - "My Rabbi: A Memoir of Milton Steinberg," Jewish Heritage, 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Journals, 1966-1967 (Box 25)